Finding Aid for the Stafford Leak Warren Papers LSC.0987
UCLA Library Special Collections
- III. Operation Crossroads Papers.
  - Assorted Memos, Reports and Dispatches., July 1946.; 53 items:
    - 7. Copy memo, Radiological Safety Section to Technical Director., July 19, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 8. Copy letter, Stanley P. Bednarczyk, Captain, MAC to Dr. E. Forrest Boyd., July 20, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 9. Copy memo, 013 E (SLW) to Deputy Commander for Technical Direction., July 21, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 10. Report, Baker Day, Radiological Safety Notes, by J.G. Ripczinske, U.S.N., July 24, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 11. Copy report, Baker Day, Radiological Safety Notes, by J.G. Ripczinske, U.S.N., July 24, 1946.; (4 duplicates, 4pp. each). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 12. Report, Report on Atomic Bomb Tests Able and Baker, Part 7, Special Reports, CJTF-One., July 1946.; (25pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 13. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, Radiaiton Safety to Burleson., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 14. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, Radiaiton Safety to Orca., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 15. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, Com. Army Air Group, JTF-One to CJTF-One., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 16. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, CTG 1.1 to Radiological Safety and others., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 17. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, DD693 MOALE to CJTF-One., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 18. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, CTU 1.1.3 to Decom. Technical Director., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 19. Copy dispatch, Director of Ship Material to CJTF-One., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 20. Copy rough readings., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 21. Copy memo, G.M. Lyon, Captain to CJTF-One., July 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 22. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, CJTF-One to JTF-One., July 29, 1946.; (3 duplicates). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 23. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, Dep. Com. Tech. to LA LAB and others., July 29, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 24. Copy CJTF=One dispatch, Technical Director K. Whiting to CTU 1.2.7., July 29, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 25. Copy naval dispatch, Dep. Com. Tech. to LA LAB and others., July 29, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 26. CJTF-One dispatch, Burleson APA67 to CJTF-One., July 30, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 27. Copy Naval Dispatch, CTG 1.5 to CJTF-One., July 29, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 28. Copy memo Frank E. Dudley, Radiological Section to Admiral T.A. Solberg., July 29, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 29. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, Burleson APA67 to CJTF-One., July 30, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 30. Copy memo, Chief, Radiological Safety Section (SLW) to Colonel James P. Cooney., July 30, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 31. Copy letter Karl T. Compton, Chairman Joint Chiefs of Staff Evaluation Board to Vice Admiral W.H.P. Blandy., July 30, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 32. Letter, DeWitt Stetten, Jr. to SLW., July 31, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 33. Copy memo, Chief of Radiological Safety Section (SLW) to J-2., August 2, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 34. List, overdoses received., undated; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 35. Memo, CJTF-One (W.H.P. Blandy) to Dr. Stuart Sturges., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 36. Copy memo, CJTF-One (W.H.P. Blandy) to Dr. Stuart Sturges., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 37. Memo, J.M. Talbot, Lieutenant Colonel M.C. to SLW., August 12, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 38. Copy memo, J.M. Talbot, Lieutenant Colonel M.C. to SLW., August 12, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 39. Copy memo, Andrew D. Bogard, Lieutenant, USNR to Chief of Radiological Safety Section., August 13, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 40. Graph, calibration of X Counter., August 15, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 41. Graph, aluminum absorption curve for fission products, Dr. Pool., undated. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 42. Graph, badges, overexposure ratios., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 43. Copy letter, Gerhard Dessauer and Dr. Herbert Scoville to Pete., October 1946. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 44. Copy naval dispatch, Director of Ship Material to CJTF-One., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 45. Rough memo, Radiaiton Safety to CJTF-One., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 46. Rough notes, Baker plus 30 days., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 47. Rough note, VAD Cochrane to VAD Blandy., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 48. Memo, from A.A. de Lorimier., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 49. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety (Haven) (SLW) to CTU 1.2 U.S.S. Fall River., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 50. Note, Statue 15 to Coyote., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 51. Rough note, Asbestos to Coyote., undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 52. Copy instructions, decontamination procedure., undated; (2 duplicates). (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 53. Copy report, Radiological Monitoring of Evaporators., undated; (13pp.). (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Memos, Dispatches and Reports., August 1946.; 54 items:
    - 1. Copy memo, J.E. Martin, Lieutenant, USNR to Commander Kauffman., August 1, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 2. Copy list, personnel badges used on Salt Lake City Lieutenant Commander R.K. Snow., undated.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 3. Copy list, permitted working time at various dates, Radiological Safety Section., August 3, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 4. Copy memo, Radiological Safety Advisor (SLW) to CJTF-One., August 3, 1946.; (6pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 5. Minutes, Medical Legal Board meetings,, R.R. Newall, Chairman., August 2-3, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 6. Copy minutes, Medical Legal Board Meetings., August 2-3, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 7. Copy minutes, Medical Legal Board Meetings., August 2-3, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 8. Copy memo Director of Ship Material (Andrew D. Bogard) to Chief, Radiological Safety Section., August 4, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 9. Minutes, Medico-Legal Board Meeting., August 4, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 10. Copy minutes, Medico-Legal Board Meeting., August 4, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 11. Letter, T.C. Lonnquest, Captain U.S. Navy to SLW., August 4, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 12. Graph, predicted activity of deposits, by R.R. Coveyou., August 4, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 13. Copy report, Operations Report of the Damage Control Safety Section O. Schneider, Captain M.C., U.S. Navy to Captain G.M. Lyon, J-015., August 4, 1946.; (49pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 14. Copy memo [report], Radiological Status of Target Ships., August 5, 1946.; (26pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 15. Report [minutes], Medico-Legal Board Meeting., August 5, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 16. Copy report [minutes], Medico-Legal Board Meeting., August 5, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 17. Copy report [minutes], Medico-Legal Board Meeting., August 5, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 18. Copy memo, Director of Ship Materials (L.A. Kniskern, Captain U.S. Navy) to Commander Task Group 1.8., August 5, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 19. Copy memo, Chief of Radiological Safety Section (SLW) to CJTF-One., August 5, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 20. Copy memo, Project Officer, Oceanography in Support of Radiological Safety (J.R. Lyman)., August 5, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 21. Cover sheet for Dr. Morgan's report., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 22. Report, Final Report of the Alpha, Beta, Gamma Survey Section, by K.Z. Morgan., August 6, 1946.; (6pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 23. Receipt, one package Top Secret, signed by W.J. McKeon., August 7, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 24. Copy CJTF-One dispatch, DSM to CJTF-One., August 7, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 25. Report, Sampling Deck of New York for Alpha Contamination, by M.G. Bowman, Los Alamos Radio-Chemistry Group., August 7, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 26. Copy report, Sampling Deck of New York for Alpha Contamination, by M.G. Bowman, Los Alamos Radio-Chemistry Group., August 7, 1946.; (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 27. Copy memo, Chief of Radiological Safety Section (SLW) to CJTF-One., August 8, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 28. Memo, Lieutenant Commander H.J. Summers to SLW., August 8, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 29. Copy memo, Chief Radiological Safety Section (SLW) to Commanding Officer, U.S. Engineers Office., August 8, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 30. Copy list, recommendations, Committee on Evaporators., undated. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 31. Memo, T.A. Shallow to Colonel de Lorimier., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 32. Memo, D.L. Collins to SLW., August 9, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 33. Memo, Scott M. Smith, Lieutenant Colonel, M.C. to SLW., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 34. Copy memo, Scott M. Smith, Lieutenant Colonel M.C. to SLW., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 35. Memo [report], Monitoring Problems, Officer in Charge of Target Ship Monitors (William A. Wulfman) to Chief Radiological Safety Section., August 9, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 36. Copy memo [summary report], Conditions of Target Ships, Chief Radiological Safety Section (SLW), to CJTF-One., August 9, 1946.; 4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 37. Copy memo, CJTF-One (W.H.P. Blandy) to Commander Task Group 1.2., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 38. Copy memo, Lieutenant R.J. Rieckhoff, USNR and Lieutenant D.W. Jones, USNR, Radiological Safety monitors to Lieutenant Commander Wulfman., August 10, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 39. Copy memo with notes, Lieutenant R.J. Rieckoff, USNR and Lieutenant D.W. Jones, USNR, Radiological Safety monitors to Lieutenant Commander Wulfman., August 10, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 40. Memo, Lieutenant Andrew D. Bogard, USNR to Chief of Radiological Safety Section., August 12, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 41. Copy memo, Lieutenant Andrew D. Bogard, USNR to Chief Radiological Safety Section., August 12, 1946.; (2 duplicates). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 42. Copy messageform, Washington Headquarters to the area engineer, USEO, Berkeley, California., September 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 43. Copy list, decontamination procedure, by J.J. Castelvecchi, Lieutenant U.S. Navy, Repair Officer., undated; (2 duplicates). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 44. Rough notes, message from Colonel de Lorimier., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 45. Cover note, for Morgan's report sent by de Lorimier., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 46. Report, Condition of Drone Boats, by K.Z. Morgan to SLW., July 28, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 47. Copy graph, Alpha-ray hazards., undated; (3 duplicates). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 48. Log, A/C radio operator., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 49. Sketch, U.S.S. Roentgen., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 50. Copy memo, 013 E (SLW) to 013., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 51. Copy dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (pass to Captain Bednarczyk)., (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 52. Copy dispatch, to Colonel Nichols., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 53. Copy list, overexposed monitors., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 54. Copy chart, tabulation of decay time, Radiological Safety Section., undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Memos, Letters and Dispatches., August 1946.; 66 items:
    - 1. Copy letter S.P. Bednarczyk, Captain MAC to Mr. A.E. Dyhre., July 20, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 2. Copy report with diagrams, Medico-Legal Board, U.S.S. Salt Lake City., August 10, 1946.; (13pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 3. Letter, K.H. Larson to SLW., August 11, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 4. Copy memo [report], Use of Soft Grits for Decontamination, Radiological Safety Advisor (SLW) to CJTF-One., August 11, 1946.; (2 duplicates, 4pp. each). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 5. Copy memo, Lieutenant Commander A.B. Cutts, USNR to SLW., August 11, 1946.; (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 6. Memo, Lieutenant Commander Herbert J. Summers, USNR to SLW., August 11, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 7. Copy check-off list, Task Group 1.2., August 12, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 8. Copy letter, George M. Lyon, Captain M.C., USNR to Admiral McIntire., August 12, 1946.; (8pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 9. Memo, Ensign W.A. Loeb, USNR to Chief, Radiological Safety Section., August 12, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 10. Copy memo, J-1 (Ralph D. Ross, Lieutenant) to all personnel in Radiological Safety Section., August 13, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 11. Copy memo [list], personnel returning to U.S.A. via U.S.S. Henrico, J-1 to all personnel of Radiological Safety Section., August 13, 1946.; (7pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 12. Copy memo, Commander Task Group 1.2 to Distribution List., August 13, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 13. Copy memo, SLW to Admiral Fahrion., August 13, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 14. Photographs, Alpha emitters on fish and scales., August 5-11, 1946.; (2 items). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 15. Copy memo, SLW to Captain A.C. Thorington., August 13, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 16. Copy minutes, Meeting of the Medico-Legal Board., August 12-13, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 17. Copy minutes, Meeting of the Medico-Legal Board., August 13, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 18. Copy memo, SLW to Commander Task Group 1.2., August 13, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 19. Copy list, overdoses, [Com. Harris to SLW]., August 14, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 20. Memo [report] with charts and graphs, Radiation Measurements on Target Submarines, C.L. Gaasterland, Commander, U.S. Navy to Director of Ship Material., August 14, 1946.; (12pp. total). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 21. Memo, A.C. Thorington, Captain, U.S. Navy to SLW., August 14, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 22. Copy dispatch, Kelly, USEO to District Engineer, USEO., August 14, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 23. Copy dispatch, Kelly, USEO to District Engineer, USEO., August 14, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 24. Letter, Jack G. Roof to Commanding Officer, Oakland Army Base., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 25. Copy letter, Stanley P. Bednarczyk, Captain, MAC to Dr. Jack G. Roof., August 15, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 26. Rough memo, Radiological Safety (Haven) to CJTF-One., undated. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 27. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (Captain Bednarczyk)., August 19, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 28. Copy memo [report], Radiological Condition of the Kenneth Whiting, Lieut. Commander W.A. Kemper, USNR to Commanding Officer, U.S.S. Kenneth Whiting., August 19, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 29. Copy memo, CJTF-One (J.A. Shackenberg) to Commanding Officers of Ships., August 19, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 30. Copy memo, Lieutenant Commander R.A. Conard, (MC), U.S. Navy and Lieutenant Cmdr. R.E. Kirch, (MC), U.S. Navy to Radiological Safety., August 20, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 31. Copy memo, Lieutenant Commander R.A. Conard, (MC), U.S. Navy and Lieutenant Commander R.E. Kirch, (MC), U.S. Navy to Radiological Safety., August 21, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 32. Copy memo, Stanley P. Bednarczyk, Captain to Commanding Officer, U.S. Engineer Office, Att: Mr. A.E. Dyhre., August 22, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 33. Copy dispatch, Kelly, USEO to Washington Liaison Office., August 23, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 34. Naval dispatch - Radiological Safety (Captain Bednarczyk to Radiological Safety Advisor)., August 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 35. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (Captain Bednarczyk and Joseph Hamilton)., August 26, 1946.; (2 copies). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 36. Memo, R.R. Coveyou to SLW., August 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 37. Telegram, K.G. Scott to SLW., August 27, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 38. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (Captain Bednarczyk)., August 27, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 39. Copy memo, George M. Lyon, Captain to Chief, Bureau of Medicine and Surgery., August 27, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 40. Copy dispatch, JTF-One Log. Off. at San Francisco to U.S.S. Henrico., August 28, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 41. Cover letter, William G. Myers, Ph.D., M.D. to SLW., August 28, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 42. Report, Observations and Suggestions Resulting from Participation in Test Able and Test Baker, William G. Myers, M.D. to SLW., August 27, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 43. Memo, E.P. Harris, Commander, MC, U.S. Navy to SLW., August 28, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 44. Copy memo, E.P. Harris, Commander, MC, U.S. Navy to SLW., August 28, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 45. Memo, R.A. Leonard to Captain S.P. Bednarczyk., August 28, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 46. Copy memo, R.A. Leonard to Captain S.P. Bednarczyk., August 28, 1946.; (2 duplicates). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 47. Copy memo, the Executive Officer to the Supply Officer., August 29, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 48. Copy memo, SLW to Major General Leslie R. Groves., August 31, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 49. Copy memo, SLW to CJTF-One., August 31, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 50. Copy memo, SLW to Dr. Herbert Scoville, Jr., August 31, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 51. Minority report, Medico-Legal Board, by R.R. Newell, Chairman., September 20, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 52. Copy dispatch, authorization of Radiological Safety instrument and equipment loan., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 53. Copy list, schedule of transit clearance of non-target ships., August 5-15, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 54. Report, Ventilation Problems and Clearance, by Ensign Walton., undated; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
      Note: for items 55-64 see also rough drafts, Box 77 folder 4, items 1-7.
    - 55. Report, Pu on Decks., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 56. Copy report, Pu on Decks., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 57. Report, Pu Hazard, Welding and Cutting., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 58. Copy report, Pu Hazard, Welding and Cutting., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 59. Report, Small Boat Clearance., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 60. Copy report, Small Boat Clearance., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 61. Report, Pu Hazard, Evaporators., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 62. Copy report, Pu Hazard, Evaporators., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 63. Report, Pu Hazard, Pipes., undated; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 64. Report, Pu Hazard, Summary., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 65-66. Rough notes., undated; (2 items). (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Memos, Letters and Dispatches., September 1946.; 16 items:
    - 1. Copy naval dispatch, Radiaiton Safety to Com. Wes. Sea Fron., September 2, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 2. Memo routing slip, Dr. Scoville to SLW., September 3, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 3. Memo routing slip, Maj. Krueger to Colonel Nichols and SLW., undated. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 4. Receipt, courier transfer, SLW, Courier, Fairfield, California to Washington D.C., September 3, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 5. Copy memo, Stanley P. Bednarczyk to Commanding Officer, U.S. Engineer Office, Att: A.E. Dyhre., September 4, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 6. Letter, Charles J. Wrobel, M.D. to SLW., September 6, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 7. Memo, Herbert Scoville, Jr. to SLW., September 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 8. Copy memo, Stanley P. Bednarczyk to Commanding Officer, U.S. Engineer Office, Att: Mr. Hawkins., September 11, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 9. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Charles J. Wrobel., September 13, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 10. Routing slip, to Captain Bednarczyk., undated. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 11. Copy dispatch, Washington H.Q. to AE USEO, Berkeley, California., September 16, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 12. Copy memo, Kenneth G. Scott to Captain Bednarczyk., September 19, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 13. Copy cover letter, W.H. Ray to Captain W.E. Walsh., September 27, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 14. Copy report, Review of Radio-Activity Protection during Decontamination of Ships, by W.H. Ray., September 27, 1946.; (7pp.). (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 15. Copy dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (Captain Bednarczyk for Cols. Nichols and Roper)., September 29, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 16. Copy memo, Chief, Bureau of Medicine and Surgery to Distribution List., September 15, 1947.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Memos, Dispatches and Reports., July-September 1946.; 61 items:
    - 1. Rough memo, Radiological Safety Section to Captain Engleman., undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 2. Rough note, tug boats., undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 3. Rough notes., undated; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 4. Copy, data sheet, lead boxes, Bikini Island, Captain R.S. Quakenbush, Director., July 25-26, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 5. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF, Att: Captain Bednarczyk., August 7, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 6. Copy report, Occupancy of Target Vessels, Radiological Safety Advisor (SLW) to CJTF-One., August 7, 1946.; (2 duplicates, 6pp. each). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 7. Rough notes., undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 8. Copy minutes, meeting Medico-Legal Board., August 10, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 9. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF., August 13, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 10. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (pass to Captain Bednarczyk)., August 14, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 11. Report, Medico-Legal Board, Appendix XX, by R.R. Newell., August 19, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 12. Copy report, Medico-Legal Board, Appendix XX, by R.R. Newell., August 19, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 13. Copy dispatch, JTF-One, Log Off. at San Francisco to U.S.S. Henrico., August 28, 1946.; (2 duplicates). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 14-47. Copies, assorted dispatches, to and from Radiological Safety Section, (attached by staples)., August 1946.; (34 items). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 48. Copy dispatch, kelly USEO to Washington Liaison Office., September 23, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 49. Copy memo, Captain Bednarczyk for SLW to Colonel Nichols., undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 50. Copy report, Initial Technical Report, Nuclear Radiation Effects in Tests Able and Baker, Preliminary Report, with cover, charts, graphs, and photographs, 013 E to 013., September 25, 1946.; (131 p. total). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 51. List, men who went to Bikini, [Buettner]., undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 53. Copy report, with graph, Radiological Monitoring of Ships Returning from Operation Crossroads, Radiological Safety Section, Medico-Legal Board., August 12-13, 1946.; (20 p.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 54. Copy report, Enclosure J, Nuclear Radiation Effects in Test A and Test B, Preliminary Report, Scoville, Stone, Hodges and Walton, approved by SLW., undated; (22pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 55. Letter, Jerry to SLW., undated; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 56. Rough report, Operation `Gadget', Report on, George M. Lyons, Captain, to Chief of Med. Section., undated; (23pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 57. Report, Appendix-Instruments., undated; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 58. Copy report, Appendix-Instruments., undated; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 59. Letter [report], Radioactivity of Rubber Washers from Blast Gauges, Commander Harris to SLW., undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 60. Copy letter [report], Radioactivity of Rubber Washers from Blast Gauges, Commander Harris to SLW., undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 61. Copy report, Collecting Samples from Ventilators., undated; (3pp.). (Box 76, Folder 5)